(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T04:29:06.797564",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
雑多に塗りたくられた
Slathered in a chaotic mess,
絵の具でぬかるんだ
muddy with paint,
世界を歩く
I walk through this world.
どこへでもゆけたけど
I could go anywhere,
どこだって同じさ
but it's all the same everywhere.
濁ったキャンバスで
On a muddy canvas,
君だけが映えていた
only you stood out brilliantly.
自分のためだけに描いた
Drawn solely for my own sake,
僕は僕以外を愛せなかった
I couldn't love anything other than myself.
息を吸い込み吐き出すそれだけの毎日に
In days consisting of just breathing in and out,
君が、君だけが映えていた
you, only you stood out brilliantly.
優しい嘘より傷つく真実が良いよ
I'd rather have a hurtful truth than a tender lie.
孤独な自由より君といる不自由が良いよ
I'd rather have the unfreedom of being with you than lonely freedom.
夢中になった 夢中になった 瞬間 五里霧中になった
I lost myself, lost myself, lost in a daze in that moment.
宇宙・未来・週末が晴れるかより 君を分かちたい
Rather than whether the cosmos, future, or weekend will clear up, I want to share you.
夢中になった 夢中になった 瞬間 筆は宙に舞った
I lost myself, lost myself, my brush danced through the air in that moment.
僕ら一つになれないし 混ざらないし濁らないし
We can't become one, we don't mix, we don't blur.
ふたり、マーブル冴える
The two of us shine in marble hues.
小さな静けさと許しと罰を分け合って
Sharing a little quiet, forgiveness, and punishment,
世界は回る
the world spins.
みんな器用に笑うようなそういうところ嫌い
I hate how everyone smiles so adeptly.
君が、君だけが本当だ
You, only you are real.
優しく奪うより傷つけても与えたいよ
Rather than taking gently, I want to give even if it hurts.
孤独で満ちるより君といて満たされずにいたいよ
Rather than being filled with loneliness, I'd rather stay unfilled while being with you.
夢中になった 夢中になった 空間 色彩 爆ぜた
I lost myself, lost myself, space and colors burst forth!
見失ってもすぐわかるのさ
Even if I lose sight of you, I'll know right away—
君は美しい
you are beautiful.
夢中になった 夢中になった 呼んだ言葉宙に舞った
I lost myself, lost myself, the words I called out danced in the air.
僕ら一つになれないし だから君に触れたかった
We can't become one, that's why I wanted to touch you.
ご覧 こんなに饒舌になったのに
Look, even though I've become so eloquent,
言いそびれたことなら山ほどあるさ
there are still mountains of things I left unsaid.
路地裏で猫を見たとか 雨上がりの夕映えが綺麗だとか
Like seeing a cat in an alleyway, or the evening glow after the rain being so pretty.
君といる不自由が心地いいとか
Like how comfortable the unfreedom of being with you is.
夢中になった 夢中になった 瞬間 五里霧中になった
I lost myself, lost myself, lost in a daze in that moment.
御大層な未来予想図より君を信じたい
Rather than a grand blueprint of the future, I want to believe in you.
夢中になった 夢中になった
Got carried away, got carried away,
瞬間 筆は宙に舞った
my brush danced in the air.
僕ら一つになれないよ
We can never become one.
混ざらないし混ざらないよ
We won't mix, we won't mix.
鳴呼 ただ二人
Ah, just the two of us.
マーブルが冴える 冴える
Marbled colors shine brightly, shine.
雑多に塗りたくられた
Slapdashly smeared over
絵の具でぬかるんだ
muddy with paint.
世界を歩く
Walking through the world,
どこへでもゆけるけど
we can go anywhere, but
どこだって同じさ
it's the same everywhere.
濁ったキャンバスで
On a muddy canvas,
僕らだけが冴えている
only we are shining bright.
はーい！ていうことでみなさん、こんぬい！不知火フレアでーす！
Hii! So everyone, konnui! It's Shiranui Flare!
今日は私の生誕祭ライブへ来てく、く、来てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
えー、1曲目は私のオリジナルソング「マーブル冴える」でした！どうだった？
Um, the first song was my original song "Marble Saeru"! How was it?
なんか、去年の8月に公開したオリジナル曲なんですけど、3Dで歌うのは今回初めてでして、
It's an original song I released last August, but this is my first time singing it in 3D,
えー、まあ、今回はですね、ま、カバー曲だけじゃなくて、オリジナル曲も、ま、ちょっと入ってたりとかするかな、みたいな感じの、手探りになっております。
so I'm kind of figuring things out as I go with both cover and original songs.
あ、そうそう、あとですね、ま、ちょっとみんな今見てて、もう気づいちゃった人いるかかんないですけど、なんとですね、ちょっと衣装が変わりました。どうでしか？かわいいでしょ？
Oh right, everyone watching right now might have already noticed, but my outfit has changed! Isn't it cute?
いろんな表情を今日は見せたいので、あのいっぱい、えー楽しんで、え、お写真もね、パシャパシャパシャパシャ、撮ってくれると嬉しいななんて思うんですけど、
I want to show you various expressions today, so I hope you'll enjoy it and take lots of photos!
あの今回のね、あのステージ見てくださいこれ。めっちゃ綺麗でしょ？今回のステージ合わせて作っていただきました！めっちょめっちょ可愛いんでしゅ！
Please look at this stage. Isn't it super pretty? It was custom-made for this! It's super cute!
ね、すごく可愛いステージになってまーす！
See, it's turned into such a cute stage!
ま、ね、今回は今年、え、屋外のステージになりました！はじめてですね、屋外。お城とか、なんかテーマパークみたいな感じで可愛く作っていただきました！
Well, this year it became an outdoor stage! It's our first time outdoors, like a castle or theme park!
そしてですね、こ、なんと、え、今年の生誕では、え、ライブ後半には、え、新章のお披露目があります。お待たせしました！100万人のお、え、ご褒美！みたいな
And for this year's birthday, in the latter half, there's a new outfit reveal. A reward for 1 million subs!
感じになってます。このステージにあった感じの衣装をね、あの考えて、え、作っていただきました！可愛い衣装になりますので、え、どんな衣装なのか、ま、予想しながら、
They designed an outfit that matches this stage! Please look forward to the reveal.
え、お披露目まで、え、お楽しみに。いや、お披露目、うん、お披露目後もお披露目前も、え、楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです！
I hope you enjoy it before and after the reveal!
え、今回のハッシュタグは、こちら！こちら！こちらですね。え、不知火フレア生誕祭2025です。感想やスクリーンショット、え、たくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
The hashtag is #ShiranuiFlareBirthday2025. Please post lots of impressions and screenshots!
それではですね、次の曲へ早速行こうと思います！え、次の曲からはゲストもたくさん登場しますので、誰が来るのかワクワクワクワクしながら楽しみに来てください！
Let's head right to the next song! Lots of guests will appear, so look forward to it!
それでは、どうぞ！
And now, here it goes!
君の心が必要で
I need your heart,
僕の心は執着だ
and my heart is persistent.
全部をひっくり返しちゃうような狂騒をくれよ！
Give me the chaos that overturns everything!
純粋でも順調でも順風でもなんだかんだ
Pure, smooth, or tailwind, one way or another,
全てがつまらないとかありえないぜ
it's impossible for everything to be boring.
説ったり 気張ったり 言い合ったり ぴーちくぱーちく
Doubting, getting tense, arguing, chit-chatting,
解決の手立てはなかなか難攻不落か？
is the solution hard to reach?
さあ ちょっと真実吟味 適当に波乱をきたせ
Now, let's examine the truth, bring some chaos.
平行線のランデブー 急がなくていいじゃないか
A rendezvous on parallel lines, no need to rush.
傾向はどうなってく？ それも心配したってノーレスポンスで
What will the trend be? Even with worry, no response.
ノーポーズで勇猛不断のストーリーに保証書はないけど
No pause, no warranty for this fearless story, but
betしてくれ、ありったけ！
bet it all!
いけないfool logic あぶないrope walkだって
It's a forbidden fool logic, a dangerous rope walk.
1000回10000回 挑戦しない理由は無い
There's no reason not to challenge it 10,000 times.
一寸先は闇だ なんて言い出ししたやつから順場にさようならだ！
Goodbye to those who said the future is darkness!
最後に笑うのは僕らだろう
We'll be the ones laughing in the end, right?
君の心が必要で
I need your heart,
僕の心は執着だ
and my heart is persistent.
あてずっぽを繰り返してしまうように見えてとしても
Even if it looks like I'm repeating wild guesses,
結局僕らが勝利しちゃうから 狂騒をくれよ！
because we'll win, give me the chaos!
晴天なり 曇天なり 荒天なり 結構、決行
Sunny, cloudy, stormy, okay, let's do it.
ノイズごときで屈服とか世話がないぜ
It's ridiculous to surrender to some noise.
竜頭蛇尾 呼鳴阿鼻 うっせえヤミー
Dragon head, snake tail, agonizing screams.
あめさざ皿まで食べるが紳士のたしなみさ
Eating everything to the last plate is a gentleman's way.
さあ いざやりやらせ 爆笑はディナーのあとで
Laughter is after dinner.
shake the world! ここにルールなんてない
Shake the world! There are no rules here.
映画の世界みたいにfree
Free, like in a movie.
一番海苔 挑戦しない理由はない
First to try, there's no reason not to take the challenge.
いっそ先が闇だなんて言い出したい奴から順番に
It's getting late, so I want to start saying...
さよならだ
"Farewell."
最後に笑うのは僕らだろう
Finally, the last ones laughing will be us, right?
君の心が必要で 僕の心は必要だ
Your heart is necessary, and my heart is necessary.
アイラブ僕繰り返しちゃうように見えてるとしても
Even if it looks like I'm repeating "I love you" over and over...
結局僕らが勝利しちゃうから競争はくれよ
Eventually we'll win, so give us some competition!
晴天なり どってなり 豪邸なり けっこけっこうの
いずごときでぐっぷと かつては分からないぜ
時折でぐっぷと かつては分からないぜ
流動だ美 共感はビューズでいい
甘ささざ波で食べるがししの嗜みさ
甘ささざ波で食べるが死しの嗜みさ
さいざや あらかぜ 爆笑はみんなのはとで
晴天なり どってなり 豪邸なり けっこけっこうの
Shake the world ここにいるなんてない
Shake the world, believing that love is right here,
映画の世界みたいにFree
is like living in a movie world!
言葉にできそうなんだ それは魔法じゃない
It sounds like something we could put into words... but even so, that's no magic trick.
Shake the world 遊んDAYたいだけ
Shake the world, just playing around,
ノリに溺れたフィクション地上 王様はピント合わなくなる
we're surely swimming in a world of fiction, where kings are no longer needed,
なら僕らはどうしよう
so what should we do?
展望を身に感じて 目は散り行きシストリキッパー
Looking out at the view, flowers scatter and limits are reached.
平行線の乱れ踏み 息絶え絶えるまで
Parallel lines running wild, breathing until we collapse!
けっこーはどうなってくー もーどーでもいいぜスムーズナンバー
What will the future hold? No matter what, it's a smooth number!
アイディアが徐々 マッパじゃなけりゃ実績エンジンで対応しろ
Alright, let's go step by step,
ジェットしてくれ ありったけ
just jet off and let it all out!
いけないfool logic でふとした情景が当たってタムラはない
It's an improper fool logic, with a bit of a plot twist at the end,
タイトオチャックで Shake the world
so let's shake the world head-on!
いけないfool logic 危ないロックを歌って一世界 一番海苔
An improper fool logic, singing a dangerous rock song, in a world where everything is upside down,
挑戦しない理由はない
there's no reason not to take the challenge.
いっそ先が闇だなんて言い出したい奴から順番に
It's getting late, so I want to start saying...
さよならだ
"Farewell."
最後に笑うのは僕らだろう
Finally, the last ones laughing will be us, right?
君の心が必要で 僕の心は必要だ
Your heart is necessary, and my heart is necessary.
アイラブ僕繰り返しちゃうように見えてるとしても
Even if it looks like I'm repeating "I love you" over and over...
結局僕らが勝利しちゃうから競争はくれよ
Eventually we'll win, so give us some competition!
願った夕方の選択の
Wishing upon an ordinary choice,
未来を今照らしていく
I'll illuminate the future right now!
微塵的な感情 ぶつけ合っちゃ
Clashing our delicate emotions,
まだ見えないね
it's still not visible yet.
逃げてきた分の距離を埋める
Filling the distance we've run away from,
ほら 飛び出でよ
let's leap out!
さいはて何て乱れなくても
Even if we can't get things right or end up completely lost,
命を燃やして 今を生きていくだけだから
we'll burn our lives and just live in the present moment!
願った存在の証明を 声を震わせ続けて
Keeping on making this sound prove our existence,
繰り返してきたから
we've kept on repeating it.
後悔はいらない 手を取り合って かそだって 受け止めて進んでいく
Regrets are unnecessary; let's hold hands and keep moving forward together,
示された答え選ぶより
rather than choosing a forced answer.
新しい夢を目指すから
Let's aim for a brand new dream!
ずっと眩しい道を歩いていこう
Walking step by step along this dazzling path,
雫を秘めた道にだって
following the path where the water droplet fell,
きっと夢はある 二人しかない可能性を ほら見つけよう
surely our dreams are real, and we should find all the possibilities we share!
さいはてよりも 今を見つめ
More than anywhere else, let's gaze at the present moment.
深い闇で どんな結末も
In the deep darkness, whatever ending awaits us,
まだ変えていけるはずだから
we can still change it.
誓った存在の証明を
The proof of our sworn existence,
ひとりいて見付けてきた空も
the sky we've found and seen all alone,
無駄じゃないと知ったから
I've learned that it wasn't all for nothing.
簡単じゃなくていい
It doesn't have to be easy,
手を取り合ってみないだって
why don't we join hands and—
受け止めて進んでいく
accept it and keep moving forward.
示された答え選ぶより
Rather than choosing the given answer,
眩しい道を歩いていこう
let's walk down the dazzling path.
深く傷ついて泣いた 冷たい風の夜
The cold, windy night when I cried, deeply hurt,
強くありたいと願った
I wished to be much stronger.
存在の証明を 声を震わせ続けて
The proof of our existence, keeping our voices trembling,
繰り返してきたから
because we've repeated it over and over.
後悔はいらない
We don't need any regrets,
手を取り合って 見えないだって
joining hands, even if we can't see,
受け止めて進んでいく
accepting it and pushing onward.
示された答え選ぶより
Rather than choosing the given answer,
新しい夢を目指すから
I'll aim for a brand-new dream.
眩しい道を歩いていこう
Let's walk down the dazzling path.
ほらまた君の前で
Look, once again in front of you,
涙を見せてしまった
I ended up showing my tears.
何があってもずっと離れないでくれた
No matter what happened, you never left my side.
誰かを守り抜くと誰かに罪を作る
To protect someone is to create sin for someone else.
生きるほど愛を知って 心は強くなる
The more we live and know love, the stronger our hearts become.
目の奥に映る過去の傷は私が飲み干すから
I will drink down the scars of the past reflected in my eyes.
君の存在だけで世界は万華鏡みたいに
Just your existence makes the world like a kaleidoscope,
くるくる回って光が射す
spinning round and round as light shines through.
変わる季節と変わらない笑い声
Changing seasons and unchanging laughter—
君は思い出にならないよ ここにいるから
you won't become just a memory, because you are right here.
真夜中ベンチで言った
That midnight on the bench,
まだかさぶたの過去を
when I painfully peeled off the scab of the past,
綺麗に剥がしたの 温かい君の手
so neatly, with your warm hand.
沈黙続いたあと 降り出す雨に気付いて
After the silence continued, noticing the falling rain,
そのまま言えずでいる
unable to say it—
ごめんね ありがとう
"I'm sorry, thank you."
月日が経つほど 純粋な
As months and days pass,
言葉は飲み込むけど
pure words are swallowed back down,
いつかまたひとりになっても星のない夜でも あの頃の孤独とは違うだろう
even if I become alone again someday, even on a starless night, it'll be different from the loneliness of those days.
泣いてばかりな青い日のわたしには
To the naive me who used to do nothing but cry,
会いたいと思う顔さえも浮かばなくて
even the face of the one I want to see won't come to mind.
桜舞う春 花火が夜空を染めていく夏
Spring where cherry blossoms dance, summer where fireworks dye the night sky...
もみじ揺れる秋
Autumn swaying with maple leaves...
雪降る冬すべてに君が居てほしい
Snow falling in winter...
すべてに君が居てほしい
I want you to be in all of it.
君の存在だけで世界は万華鏡みたいに
Just by your presence, the world...
万華鏡みたいに くるくる回って
Spins around like a kaleidoscope,
光が射す
And the light shines through.
変わる季節と変わらない笑い声
With changing seasons and unchanging laughter,
走る君に合わせ景色は色付くから
The scenery matching you as you run becomes colorful.
どうか忘れないで 今その目に映る幸せ
Please don't forget the happiness...
今その目に映る幸せ
Reflected in your eyes right now.
最高ですか？ 最高です！
Is it the best? It's the best!
幸せですか？ 幸せです！
Are you happy? I'm happy!
最高ですか？ 最高です！
Is it the best? It's the best!
幸せですか？ 幸せです！
Are you happy? I'm happy!
お付き合いしちゃって
Let's start dating already,
同棲とか始めちゃって
Or even start living together!
好き好き 大好き 困っちゃうジャン
I like you, I love you, I adore you so much it's troubling!
新郎新婦になりたいー！
I want to become a bride and groom!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ ハイ！ハイ！ぺこマリ
Pekomari!
ぺこるとマリンはてぇてぇ
PekoMori is tee-tee!
婚約指輪はどうするの？
What should we do about engagement rings?
給料半年分ぐらい？
About half a year's salary?
新居の間取りはどうするの？
What about the floor plan for our new home?
ナナELDDDK（えー）
N-N-N-LDK (Eh?)
世界一可愛くなるから
So you'll be the cutest in the world,
世界一かっこよくいてね！
And be the coolest in the world, okay?
愛してるも毎日言って
Tell me you love me every day,
あと「大好き」も忘れずに！
And don't forget to say "I love you" too!
お父さんお母さん お許しください結婚します
Mom and Dad, please give us your blessing, we're getting married!
ご祝儀！ もっともっともっともっと 積んでいいぺこー？
Congratulations! Let's pile up more and more and more!
おお願い
Please!
人生最高の日に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
Two people receiving blessings,
好き好き 大好き 困っちゃうジャン
Like, like, love so much it's troubling!
新郎新婦の入場
The bride and groom's entrance!
大好きな人 大切な人 ちゃんと手をつないで生きていきますCHU
Living life hand in hand with the person I love most, the person who is most precious to me!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ ぺこマリ
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! PekoMari!
ぺこるとマリンはてぇてぇ
PekoMori is tee-tee!
新婚旅行はどうしよう？
What should we do for our honeymoon?
沖縄で水着とか着たい！
I want to wear swimsuits in Okinawa or somewhere!
ホテルでは何を食べようか？
What should we eat at the hotel?
私の手作り料理（なんで？）
My handmade cooking (What's that?)
世界一可愛いお前と 生涯添い遂げると誓う
Vowing to spend a lifetime with you, the cutest in the world,
愛してるって毎日言うよ
Saying "I love you" every day!
dear pretty pretty my sweetest rabbit
おじいちゃんおばあちゃん 娘もついに結婚します
Grandpa and Grandma, your daughter is finally getting married!
子育ての秘訣？
The secret to raising children?
そうね夫婦として当たり前のことを 当たり前にやるだけなんだけれどしいて言うならば 二人の愛
Well, it's just doing what's obvious as a couple, as you'd naturally expect!
人生最高の日に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
Two people receiving blessings,
好き好き 大好き 困っちゃうジャン
Like, like, love so much it's troubling!
新郎新婦の入場
The bride and groom's entrance!
大好きな人 大切な人 ちゃんと手をつないで生きていきます
Living life hand in hand with the person I love most, the person who is most precious to me!
もうさぁ、落ち！
Fall!
人生最高の日に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
Two people receiving blessings,
好き好き 大好き 困っちゃうジャン
Like, like, love so much it's troubling!
新郎新婦の入場
The bride and groom's entrance!
大好きな人 大切な人 ちゃんと手をつないで生きていきます
Living life hand in hand with the person I love most, the person who is most precious to me!
触れなさい、最近
Touch me, recent style!
最高ですか？ 最高です！
Is it the best? It's the best!
幸せですか？ 幸せです！
Are you happy? I'm happy!
最高ですか？ 最高です！
Is it the best? It's the best!
幸せですか？ 幸せです！
Are you happy? I'm happy!
ウォンチュ ゲッチュ 見つげっちゅ ウォンチュ
Wantchu, getchu, mitsu getchu, wantchu!
主義主張で弾けたB.B.マイ・ルーレット
Bursting with ideology and claims: B.B. My Roulette!
グッとスタート　切っ先溶けた
A sudden start, the blade's tip melted away.
いーとーいーとーいーとー
I-to-i-to-i-to-i-to!
永久戦術・気まぐれのQ　1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Eternal tactic, fickle Q, diving into a 1-millimeter gap!
ラブスタンプ全部コンプ・セイント・アップ
All love stamps completely comped, saint up!
イーゾ　イーゾ　イーゾ　イーゾ　せーのっ！
I-zo, i-zo, i-zo, i-zo, ready, go!
「今日はちょっとメンタル…」
"Today's mental is a bit..."
いやさましきチャレンジャー
Nay, a severe challenger!
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental.
大支給！大好き！　1・2・3・はい！
Dai-shikyu! Dai-suki! One, two, three, go!
まみむめも、めも、めも、見れないのっ
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, mo, mo, I can't look!
立ち尽くして、て、て、手が触れて
Standing still, hands touching—
大支給！大好きになれっ！
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me!
もっときゅーきゅーきゅーきゅーと強制ろっ
More Q-Q-Q-Q and force it!
あのねクリオネすけてるハート
You know, the clear heart of a clione,
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But don't see right through this chest of mine!
大支給！大好きになれっ！
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me!
あたしじゃないなんて終わってんね！
Saying it's not me is so over!
ウォンチュ ゲッチュ 見つげっちゅ ウォンチュ
Wantchu, getchu, mitsu getchu, wantchu!
空振りキューティマイル・レッド
A swing-and-miss cutie mile red,
ちょっと息継ぎ・大休止
A little breath-catching, big rest!
いやいやいやいや　でも　せーのっ！
No, no, no, no, but ready, go!
「今日は求めて！」
"Today, crave it!"
ぶらわしきチャレンジャー
Brawling challenger,
はっと書いたオートメーション
A suddenly written automation.
大支給！大好き！　1・2・3・はい！
Dai-shikyu! Dai-suki! One, two, three, go!
まみむめも、めも、めもにしてほしいの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, mo, mo, make it for me!
なになに、ねこねこ、恋のこねこと
What-what, cat-cat, a love kitten—
大支給！大好きになれっ！もっときーきーきーきーと強制ろっ
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me! More K-K-K-K and force it!
あのねマリオネ　操られレディ
You know, a marionette, controlled lady,
でもねそれも悪くはないね　大支給！大好きになれっ！
But you know, that's not so bad either! Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me!
あたしじゃないなんて終わってね！
Saying it's not me is so over!
ズレ　取り合ふりして　周波数を　見逃さないで
Pretending to miss each other, don't miss the frequency!
誘惑の　迷宮リスナー　リアルに鳴り止み合おう
Tempting maze listener, let's keep ringing together realistically!
まみむめも、めも、めも　見れないのっ　立ち尽くして、て、て、手が触れて
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, mo, mo, I can't look! Standing still, hands touching—
大支給！大好きになれっ！もっときゅーきゅーきゅーきゅーと強制ろっ
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me! More Q-Q-Q-Q and force it!
あのねクリオネ　透けてるハート　でもねこの胸見透かさないで
You know, the clear heart of a clione, but don't see right through this chest of mine!
大支給！大好きになれっ！あたしじゃないなんて終わってんね！
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me! Saying it's not me is so over!
まみむめも、めも、めも　見れないのっ　立ち尽くして、て、て、手が触れて　大支給！大好きになれっ！
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, mo, mo, I can't look! Standing still, hands touching—Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me!
もっときゅーきゅーきゅーきゅーと強制ろっ
More Q-Q-Q-Q and force it!
あのねクリオネ　透けてるハート　でもねこの胸見透かさないで
You know, the clear heart of a clione, but don't see right through this chest of mine!
大支給！大好きになれっ！あたしじゃないなんて終わってんね！
Dai-shikyu! Fall in love with me! Saying it's not me is so over!
どこまでも続くこの空のように
As far as this endless sky,
ずっと　ずっと　ずっと
Always, always, always
青く想って…
Thinking of blue...
遥か遠くまで
To the distant far horizon,
青く在れ
Stay blue!
過ぎ去った日々と　記憶の回路に沿って
Following the circuitry of memories of days gone by,
心の内側が　母音を伝うんだ
The voice of my heart conveys the vowels.
失ったピースを数えて　またどうしてか　手を伸ばすんだ　胸の奥
Counting the lost pieces, why do I once again reach out deep inside my heart?
分かっているよ　進む意味を　君はくれたんだ
I know the meaning of moving forward, you gave it to me.
どこまでも続くこの空を
This endless sky...
As far as this endless sky,
駆け抜けて　鮮やかな青になれたら
Running through it, if I could become vivid blue,
どこまでも響く旅になる
It becomes a journey echoing forever.
大袈裟でもいい　咲き誇れ　ただ伝えたいから
Even if it's an exaggeration, bloom proudly, just because I want to convey it.
言葉が今　音になって
My words now turn into sound.
空振った日々の 孤独なアイロニー
An irony of lonely days, swinging and missing,
ずっと 声にならない 心の奥の「本当」
The "truth" deep inside my heart that never becomes a voice,
気付かなかった フリをして誤魔化した
I pretended not to notice and brushed it aside.
揺らげる戦慄 滲む青
A wavering tremor, a bleeding blue.
何度だって 塗り直すよ
No matter how many times, I'll repaint it,
消せない程に
To a degree that cannot be erased.
どこまででも 続くこの空も
Even this sky stretching on forever,
きっとなら怖くない
Surely won't be frightening,
風追い越して
Outrunning the wind!
どこまででも行けるさ 思うまま
We can go anywhere, however we please—
描く未来も 超えてゆけ さあ
Surpass the future we paint, come on!
派手なくらいに想いを 今 音に乗せて
Pouring our feelings into the sound, as boldly as can be.
まぶたの裏 見える景色
The scenery visible behind my eyelids,
君の声で 気づけた あの日の青
That blue of that day I realized through your voice.
In to the skies with you, forever they'll be blue
Into the skies with you, forever they'll be blue.
歌い続けるよ
I will keep singing.
どこまでだって 響くさ きっと
No matter how far, it will surely echo.
不器用だっていい 恥じるな
It's okay to be clumsy, don't be ashamed.
笑われたっていい 止まるな この気持ちは消えないから
It's okay to be laughed at, don't stop, because this feeling won't fade.
どこまででも 続くこの空を
This sky stretching on forever,
駆け抜けて 鮮やかな青になれたら
If we dash through and become a vibrant blue—
どこまででも 響く歌になる
It will become a song echoing endlessly,
大袈裟でもいい さきほこれ
Even if it's an exaggeration, bloom forth!
ただ伝えたいから 言葉より 今 音になって
Because I just want to convey it, turning into sound right now rather than words.
青く染まるよ
We will be dyed in blue.
手加減できないよ 指噛んじゃうよ
No holding back, I might bite my finger!
フレアフェスティバルだ！ めっちゃ楽しそうなんだけどここ！
It's Flare Festival! It looks super fun here!
でしょ？ しかも Iris、It's IRyS from hololive English! Hololive English IRyS today!
Right? Plus, IRyS from Hololive English! Hololive English IRyS today!
今日は来てくれてどうもありがとうございました。 チャンネル登録、高評価、いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today. Thank you always for subscribing and giving likes!
あの、どうですか？ おりょく……なんですよ、私とIRISの初めての……
Um, how is it? It's our first duet... between me and IRyS...
どうだった？ 青く染まる めちゃくちゃえもい曲やろ？
How was it? "Aoku Somaru" is a super emotional song, right?
ねえ、なんでこの曲出したかみたいのね、まああの話してると思うんだけどさ、
Hey, we probably talked about why we released this song, but...
あの、出したときにね、あのフータが声かけてくれてさ。フータがおりょく出すそうよってめっちゃ嬉しそうにしてくれて、
When we released it, Fuuta reached out to me. Fuuta seemed so happy, saying "Let's release a duet song!"
ふたりでさ、あのいろいろね、あの、エモいゲームをね、
The two of us playing various spicy, emotional games...
エモいゲームをやってるんで、いくらおらんかくしたりとか色々してるわけよ。
Doing emotional gacha pulls, doing Ikura gacha, and all sorts of things.
なんですけど、あの、やっぱりね、二人とも歌がね、好きで歌活動とかもね、してるわけで、
But you know, both of us really love singing and do music activities as well,
そうなので、私、あの、まあ、おりょくとかを、あの、作る過程で、あの、聞いた曲、
So when I was making the duet, songs I listened to...
の中で、あ、もうこれめちゃめちゃIRISと歌いたいって思った曲が、あったりとかして、ステキな曲出して、それはやるに決まってる！IRISに、うん、一緒に歌わない？って聞いたら、
Among them, I thought "Ah, I really want to sing this with IRyS," and when I asked IRyS, "Won't you sing it with me?",
いやだあって言ったんだよね。そしたら、亡くなったんです。
She said "No way." And then she vanished!
そう、いまのは、この、この世界線はまた別の世界線だからね。受け入れた世界線だからね。
Yeah, that was in another worldline. It's a worldline we accepted.
そう。だから、現実とは違うんだよね、みんな。そう、現実はね、断ってから、
Exactly. So it's different from reality, everyone. In reality, she turned it down...
あの、これ終わったあと、あの、泣かしたことになっちゃうから、この曲。やめて！泣かしたことになんないで。
And after this, it'd sound like I made her cry with this song. Stop! Don't make it sound like that!
まあね、私とね、IRISで、またね、歌いたいけどね、こういうの。ね、またやりたいね、歌。
Well, you know, IRyS and I want to sing together again. Yeah, I want to sing again.
歌はあんまりやってないからね、最初。そう。いつも言われてたの、なんかリスナーさん、フレアリスが好きなリスナーさんには、
We haven't done much singing at first. Yeah. Listeners always told us—Flare's fans—
ふたりのなんか曲、出さないのっていつも言われてたの。そうなの？そうだよ。だから、そう言ってもらえて嬉しいな。
"Aren't you guys releasing a song together?" They always asked. Is that so? Yeah. So I'm so happy to hear that.
うん、なので、また歌おうよ！歌う、うん。あと、なんか、あの、サバイバルも、サバイバル、森でのサバイバル、
Yeah, so let's sing again! Let's sing. Also, you know, survival... survival in the forest,
そうよ、森のサバイバルとか、なんか...
That's right, like surviving in the forest or something...
いくらもとろう...
We'll catch lots of salmon roe...
一狩りもしようよ。
Let's go on a hunt too.
一狩り？
A hunt?
一狩りもしようよ。
Let's go on a hunt.
一狩りもしたいね。
I want to go on a hunt too.
ってことでね、はい。
So yeah, yep.
またね、あの、フレアアイリスは今後もね、あの、いっぱい続いてきますんで、
And hey, Flare Iris will continue a lot more from now on,
フレアアイリスこれからもよろしくお願いします！
so please keep supporting Flare Iris!
よろしくお願いします！いえーい！いえーい！
Thank you very much! Yay! Yay!
あ、私がはくんだっけ？あそうだ、はい、はくんだよ！
Ah, is it my turn? That's right, I'm gonna wrap up!
はける！はける！
I can do it! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
と言うことで知らぬ火フレア生誕祭、まだまだ続きます！
So Shiranui Flare's birthday festival continues still!
おまちかねの新曲は、まあ、そろそろかな？ちょっとこれだとわかんないですけど。
The long-awaited new song, well, is it about time? Hmm, I don't really know from just this.
まあ、次だけ、いきましょう！
Well, let's just go to the next one!
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) If you're dealing with woes
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Or not quite human
(Be happy!) 弘まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Aim for it proudly
(Undead) 生きていんだし
(Undead) Because you're alive
目を逸した過去も
The past you looked away from
退屈な未来も
And that boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ
Still counseling you, oh well
古今東西 ピースピース
Universal peace, peace
(Unhappy?)
(Unlucky?)
(Be happy!)
(Undead)
ねえねえ ねえねえ なんだかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, why does it feel like I'm fighting someone?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Untouchable, don't even want to touch
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分 ともうとっくに死んでる
The past me, me, me, me, already long dead
透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost
幼気で痛い記憶の奥 残念? もう居ないのに
Deep in childish, painful memories. Too bad? Even though they're gone
あれ? そっちが良い? アイロニーね
Huh? That's better? Such irony
透かされているのは現在の自分? ナンスン 消えないレター
Is the current me transparent? Nonsense, an indelible letter
Yes! 要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれてるみたい
Yes! In short, a complex. It's like I'm possessed
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
Wrapped tight and won't let go, my former self
Undead 死んじゃいない お前と前の連鎖
Undead, you're not dead. You and your chain
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing on and on
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑劣だ
Not even trying to be happy is cowardly
この世 この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Who knows what comes next, an ogre or a snake?
出会って遭って やっと始まる物語
Meeting and crossing paths, the story finally begins
さあ人が怪物か 閑話休題 ピースピース
Now, human or monster? Back to topic, peace peace
Past & future Can't change the past Past & future Run for the future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ 何の希望もない期待できないような気がして
Somehow feeling like there's no hope or expectation for the future
もう随分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
Living long enough, jaded by déjà vu and templates, no sign of wonderful events
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と 退屈な進化
Too bad, accumulated experiences, fossilized myths and boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった慣れちゃったなんて 整えていくガイダンス
I just want thrills. Bored, used to it, guidance organizing it
増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい 吸い尽くして
Increasing compliance, getting covered up, sucking it all dry
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This one and that one all taste the same
Undead 死んじゃいない お前と前の連鎖
Undead, you're not dead. You and your chain
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, past, future, and present exist right now
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Fulfill your life faithfully, aim for a happy ending
Undead 死んじゃいない お面に言っているんだよ
Undead, you're not dead, I'm telling you
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is as good as dead, a corpse undead
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) If you're dealing with woes
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Or not quite human
(Be happy!) 弘まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Aim for it proudly
(Undead) 生きていんだろ
(Undead) Because you're alive
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Drowning in unhappiness or finding happiness
そう全部全部 お前だ
It's all, all up to you
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Universal, all creations, peace peace
Past & future Can't change the past Past & future Run for the future
人の在る所に いつも憂い事 生き抜け この化物ばかりの物語
Where people gather, there are worries. Survive this tale of monsters!
POP IN POP IN 2
かくして どこへどこへどこへも連れてって
Hide it, take me anywhere, anywhere
ひみつ デート キミはキミはキミは探せるかな？
Secret date, can you, can you find me?
あらわる あたしは 行く先々 あと先ざきなら考えない
I appear everywhere I go, not thinking ahead
パカラパカラ！ 馬もびっくり 玉手箱 手取り早く トリコになれ
Clippity-clop! Surprising even horses, become captivated quickly
だって アクタ だけじゃ足りないでしょ 一瞬 たりとも離れない がぶっ！
Because just an acrylic stand isn't enough, right? Won't leave you for a second - chomp!
あらいぶ ポップうー よそ見しないでね 愛 あらわる 結局は おんりゅうー じゃん！
I love you pop you, don't look away, in the end it's only you!
行く 先々 現る ポップうらーびゅー ずーっと隣でね
Appearing everywhere I go, always by your side
ポッケから pop in 忍ばせ pop in 2 踏んだり蹴ったり pop in かくれんぼ boy
Pop in from the pocket, stealthily pop in 2, stepping on it pop in, hide-and-seek boy
ポッケから pop in 忍ばせ pop in 2 ひょん！ 現る pop in アイドル... pop in happy 2 u！
Pop in from the pocket, stealthily pop in 2, boing! Pop in idols appear... pop in happy 2 U!
か・くして
Hide...
どこへ どこへ どこへも 連れでって
Take me anywhere, anywhere, anywhere!
ひ・みつ デート
Secret date,
キミ は キミ は キミ は 探せる か な ？
Can you, can you, can you find me?
現る アタシ は 行く 先々
I appear everywhere I go.
あと 先 ざき なら 考え ない
I don't think about the future.
パ・カラパカラ ！ 馬 も びっくり 玉手箱
Clippity-clop! Even horses are surprised.
手取り早く トリコ に なれ
Quickly become captivated by me.
だって アクスタ だけ じゃ 足りない でしょ ？
After all, just an acrylic stand isn't enough, right?
一瞬 たりとも 離れ ない が ぶっ ！
I won't leave you for even a moment—chomp!
アイ ラブ ユー ポップ ユー
I love you, pop you!
よそ見 し ない で ね
Don't look away, okay?
愛 あらわ に 結局 は オンリー ユー ！
With love laid bare, in the end it's only you!
行く 先々 現る
Appearing everywhere I go,
ポップ ユー ラブ ユー ず 〜 っと 隣 で ね
Pop you, love you, always by your side!
ポッケ から pop in
Pop in from the pocket,
忍ばせ pop in 2
Stealthily pop in 2.
踏んだり蹴ったり pop in
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
かくれん boy
Hide-and-seek boy!
ポッケ から pop in
Pop in from the pocket,
忍ばせ pop in 2
Stealthily pop in 2.
乙女 乙女 乙女 の 上飯し で
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
ひ・みつシェイク
Hide-and-seek boy!
甘く甘く甘くかき混ぜるの
Pop in from the pocket,
群がるヤツらは行く先々
Stealthily pop in 2.
歌えば列ができちゃうじゃん
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
ガラガラバヤボひっくり返るよ館
Hide-and-seek boy!
てっとり早くキュートになれあー
Pop in from the pocket,
キラキラ回る星にのってお手々自体をまわしても
Stealthily pop in 2.
一足飛びになる仕組みは謎 ガッ ？
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
アイラブユーポッピー置いとかないでね
Hide-and-seek boy!
相場は次第全力現るりゆうだ
Pop in from the pocket,
行く先々絡まるポピュラービューズ
Stealthily pop in 2.
ずっと繋いでね
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
ポッケから pop in くるわせ pop in 2
Hide-and-seek boy!
ブラッドネーション
Pop in from the pocket,
ポッケから pop in くるわせ pop in 2 よッ ！
Stealthily pop in 2.
隠れる pop in idol
Hiding pop in idol...
アイアイアイアイ アイアイアイアイ
Pop in happy 2 u!
とくアイアイアイアイ アイアイアイアイ とく
Pop in!
アイアイアイアイ アイアイアイアイ とく
うー pop in
Pop in!
うー pop in pop in 2
Pop in 2!
うー pop in
Pop in!
うー pop in pop in 2
Pop in 2!
どこそこどこそこどこわかるかな
Do you know where, where, where it is?
席替ぎ魔理沙 このりふぁー
Stealing away your seat—how's this, uneasy?
どこどこどこどこどこわかるかな
Do you know where, where, where it is?
どこにいったってきみが一番
Wherever you go, you are the best!
ねえ遊んで変わる変わるきせかえここれいたよこ
Hey, let's play, changing and swapping worlds!
あたたぷーぷ天国地獄お地獄可愛いわ作れるともっとく
Heavenly or earthly, cute things can be created infinitely!
ねえいつでも呼んでついてく360°
Hey, call me anytime, following 360 degrees!
ドックドックむちゅちゅドック
Dock, dock, munch, munch, chug, chug, dock!
アイラブポピュ置いとかないでね
I love you, pop you! Don't leave me, okay?
愛増し増し全力現るりゆうだ
With love laid bare, it's the full-power appearance story!
アイラブポピュよそうみしないでね
I love you, pop you! Don't play around, okay?
アイあらわに結局はおりゆうじゃん
I appear everywhere I go.
行く先々現るポピュラービューズ
Take me anywhere, anywhere, anywhere!
ずっと隣でね
Always by your side, okay?
ポッケから pop in
Pop in from the pocket,
忍ばせ pop in 2
Stealthily pop in 2.
踏んだり蹴ったり pop in
Adding insult to injury, pop in,
かくれん boy
Hide-and-seek boy!
ポッケから pop in
Pop in from the pocket,
忍ばせ pop in 2
Stealthily pop in 2.
現る pop in idol
Hiding pop in idol...
pop in happy to you
happy to you
happy to you happy to you
pop in
pop in 2
ありがとうー ！
Thank you so much!
ホロライブ 3期生 の みんな に 来 て いただき まし た ー ！
Thank you all so much for coming today!
おめでとー ！
Happy birthday!
お誕生日 おめでとう ー ！
Happy birthday to you!
本当 に どうも ありがとう 、 ありがとう ！
Thank you so much!
じゃあ 自己 紹介 し とき ます か ？
Let's do a self-introduction.
し ます し ます 。
Let's do that!
じゃあ あの 、 ペコ ちゃん から どうぞ 。
Then let's start with Pekora-chan.
ぺこ ぺこ ぺこ ！
Peko-peko-peko!
ホロライブ 3期生 の 兎田ぺこら と ──
Hololive 3rd Gen's Usada Pekora, and...
はい ！ みなさん こん まぁ する ！ ホロライブ 3期生 白銀ノエル と ──
Hello, everyone! It's Hololive 3rd Gen's Shirogane Noel!
あほーい ！ ホロライブ 3期生 宝鐘 海賊団 船長 の 宝鐘マリン です ー ！
Ahoi! It's Hololive 3rd Gen's Marine Houshou, captain of the Houshou Pirates!
そして ──
And finally...
えー 、 不知火 けん の 、 えー 、 不知火フレア です ！ よろしく お願い し ます ！
It's Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen! Nice to meet you!
ホロライブ 3期生 です ！
I'm from Hololive 3rd Gen!
さあ 、 3期生 4人 合わせ て ──
Let's all sing together!
ホロライブ ！ ホロライブ ！
Hololive! Hololive!
pop in 2 ！
Pop in 2!
いい ん じゃ ない ？
That was good, right?
一体感 、 一体感 あっ た 。
There was a sense of unity!
いや 、 色々 気 に なる ところ が ある ん だ けど 、
Yeah, there were a lot of things I was curious about, but...
どう し て も 真っ先 に 触れ たい の は この かわい いーーーっ ！
More than anything, I just wanted to touch on how cute this is!
かわいい ！ かっ かわいい ！
So cute!
でも 先 に 曲 の 話 と か する ？
Shouldn't we talk about the song first?
かわいい ん だ けど ──
It's so cute, but...
そう 、 今日 は ね 、 みんな と 一緒 に 歌い たく て ──
So, today, I really wanted to sing with everyone...
はい 、 一緒 に 歌っ た ん です けど 、
I've been singing live with them, but...
あ、ほんとにね、あの、ここ、ここ着た、着たいみたいなところがね、おのおのあって、
We each had specific parts we really wanted in our outfits,
そうそうそう！だから、ちょっと箇所振りをね、
That's right! So we divided up the spots
みんなが一番なんか、可愛いところをね、
so that everyone could show their cutest side.
いや、はい、歌い出しの箇所振りがまいなと思って、
We figured out who would sing which part,
で、それだけじゃなくて、あの、その前に歌ったアンデッドのね、コーラスもさ、
and not just that, for the Undead chorus we sang right before—
あ、やったやった！アンデッド、ね、結構、とっとでやったね。
Ah, we did! For Undead, we really went for it.
そうなの、マリンがね、え、ちょっとちょっと！あんた可愛いね、その衣装！
That's right. Marine's—hey, wait a minute! Your outfit is so cute!
いやそうだよ、可愛い！
That's right, it's so cute!
なにその、後ろの、天使ちゃんみたいな可愛い、可愛い、可愛い！
What is that cute angel-like thing on the back? So cute!
ちょっと紹介、じゃあ足元から順番にちょっと見てみようか。
Let's introduce them one by one, starting from the feet.
はい、ご覧ください、こちらのこの可愛いブーティーなブーツ！
Take a look at these cute booties!
ちょっとね、リボン感のあるレースがね、ついてて可愛いですよね。
They have ribbon-like lace, which is super cute, right?
ちょっと上に上がって、じゃて、あーらお尻までもちょっと可愛い、可愛いでしょう？
Moving up a bit... look, even the back is so cute, right?
あ、リボンも後ろも可愛い！リボンも可愛い！
Ah, the ribbon on the back is cute too! The ribbon is cute!
本当にね、ちょっとオレンジにもなってて、リボンもあって、なんかね、
It's really orange, with ribbons too, and...
なんか、イメージ的には、こうなんかこの年中、年中切れる制服衣装みたいな感じのさ、
Concept-wise, it's like a school uniform outfit you can wear all year round.
めちゃくちゃいいじゃん！ね、じゃあちょっとおなか周りから行きいいですか？
That's amazing! Shall we move around the waist area?
あーら可愛い！ね、可愛い！
Oh, how cute! So cute!
あーら後ろも可愛いわね！お, なんかすごい羽みたいな、エルフれみたいだね、なんかね。
Oh, the back is cute too! It's got wings like an elf, doesn't it?
ね、可愛い！スパタイちゃいそうだよ。エルフの妖精さんになれたかな。
Right, cute! You look like an elf fairy.
じゃあお顔、髪型とかも見る？え、可愛い！髪型の優勝しとるで！
Shall we check the face and hairstyle? Wow, cute! That hairstyle is a total winner!
ちょっと顔結んだんだこれ、ミッスラ、なになにつけてんの？これ何つけてんの？
Tied up like this... Missla, what is that attached? What is that?
あら、ブローチみたいなのついて、可愛い、可愛い、あ、ここ、編み込み可愛いわね、あんたそれ！
Oh, there's a brooch-like thing, cute! And the braids are so cute, you!
髪型もあるのね、可愛いわね、優勝です。
You've got that hairstyle too, so cute! You win.
いやでも、マリンとしては1個気になるな。なになに？マリンのがある？
But as Marine, there's one thing I'm curious about. What is it? Is there something for Marine?
ロスエス？1枚脱げないのかな？え、脱げないの？
Los S? Can you take one off? Eh, you can't take it off?
脱げないの、それちょっと1枚くらい？いや、これはね、なんと脱げま…え、脱げ…
You can't take it off? Even just one? Well, actually, it can... wait, can it?
え、脱げない、脱げない！
Eh, you can't take it off!
え、じゃあちょっと、でもちょ、ちょっとだけ脱げる、ちょっとだけ。え、脱いで来て、脱いできて、脱いできて！
Eh, well, just a little bit can come off. Go take it off!
大丈夫なのかな？どこ脱いでくんだろ？じゃあじゃあ、マリンが1枚脱ごうかな。いや、可愛いよ。
Is that okay? Where are they taking it off? Well, I'll take one off. No, it's cute.
脱ぎましたよ！え？どこどれ？
I took it off! Eh? Where? Which one?
あーら可愛いわね！ちょっとじっくり見せて、おばさんに服見せて。
Oh, how cute! Let me take a good look, show the auntie your clothes.
ほら可愛い！わあ可愛い！ちょっとめちゃいいじゃん！え、え、背中が？可愛い！
Look how cute! Wow, cute! This is so nice! Wait, the back? Cute!
ちょっと腕上げてみてよ、こうやって。万歳、はい万歳！はい、くるり。あら可愛い！
Try raising your arms like this. Hands up! Now spin around. Oh, how cute!
ええ、可愛い！めちゃんこいい！ヒープなしもいいね！ヒープ取れてもめちゃんこ可愛い！
Wow, cute! Super nice! Without the cape is nice too! Even without it, it's super cute!
いや、実はこの衣装まだちょっともう一個ね、秘密があって、まだあるんだよ。
Actually, this outfit has one more secret, there's more.
もっといいんですか？もっと脱げるのか？脱げないけど、になってて。
Is there more? Can you take more off? You can't, but...
え、それ以上？それ以上、どこ、サービスだぞと。
Eh, even more? Beyond that, where? It's fan service.
え、サービス？サービスきた！
Eh, service? Service is here!
お願いします！なんだなんだ！見せて見せて！どうかちら！
Please! What is it? Show us! Let's see!
うわ、可愛いわね！ちょっと変わる！
Wow, how cute! It changes a bit!
星空というか、ね、なんか、せ、生活みたいな感じをイメージして、
Kind of like a starry sky, imagining daily life or something,
ちょっとだけあの、ほん、というか、水色っぽい感じのね、感じにしてみました！
I tried making it a light blue-ish vibe!
私好きだわ、ずっと見ていたい！みんな写真撮ってや、パシャパシャ！
I love it, I want to keep looking at it! Everyone take pictures, snap snap!
たくさん写真撮ってね！全然衣装変わるね、変わった！
Take lots of photos! The outfit totally changes, it changed!
これね、帽子も実はなんか取れたりとかする。ちょっとみんなご覧なさいよ、帽子もちょっと脱いでごらん。
And actually, the hat can come off too. Look everyone, try taking off the hat.
なんとフリーア行くぜ！行ったり来たり、ファッションショー楽しいね！
We're going free! Back and forth, a fashion show is so fun!
せー、ファッションショーよ。
Right, a fashion show.
お、あま、まだまだまだ、まだだよ。まだまだだよ。じゃあじゃあ、急がないで。そう、じっくり脱げばいいんだから。
Oh, not yet, not yet. Calm down, take your time taking it off.
あ、脱げた？お、なんかごみ付いてたみたいで。あ、ら、可愛いじゃないの！
Ah, it came off? Oh, looks like some trash was attached. Oh, how cute!
え、ちょっとじゃ見えなかった頭の後ろ側をちょっと見せちゃおうよ。
Let's show the back of the head that we couldn't see before.
あ、こうやってね！こうやってね！可愛いね！やってるベコー。ら、可愛いわ！
Like this! Like this! So cute! Oh, how cute!
これあ、最高ですね。最高。
This is the best. The best.
ありがとうございます！可愛くデザインしていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! It was designed so cute. Thank you!
とっても可愛いです！なんかそのうちみんなでさ、衣装きて歌いたいね！
It's so cute! Someday we should all wear these outfits and sing together!
なんかですけどね
Well, sort of...
あ、えでも
Ah, well...
さっき歌ったじゃん、歌った歌った
You sang just a minute ago, didn't you?
あ、そっか、そっか、そっか、オッケー
Ah, I see, I see. Okay.
あら、かわいいわね。素敵ね、ぷらちゃんじゃあこのままで4人でなんかやろっか
Aww, how cute. So cute, Pura-chan. Let's keep it like this and do something with the four of us!
じゃあ今から歌おうね、今から
Well, let's sing from now on, starting now!
今日はみんなありがとね
Thank you all so much today!
あれ、みんなありがと
Oh, thank you everyone!
じゃああの、お疲れ様
Well then, good work everyone!
お疲れ様
Good work!
お疲れ様、お疲れ様、ありがとね
Great job, thank you so much!
お元気で
Take care!
追い出そう、追い出そう、めっちゃ追い出そうやん
Let's kick them out, kick them out! Let's totally kick them out!
おめでとう、本当、おめでとう
Congratulations, truly, congratulations!
ありがとうね、可愛い
Thank you, so cute!
はあ、楽しかったなあ
Ah, that was so much fun!
ということでですね、えー、次の曲は、え、パレードで、みんなでちょっと盛り上がりたいなということで、ま、ちょっとみんなを追い出しちゃってごめんねなんですけど、
So with that said, for our next song, we're doing a parade, and I wanted us all to get hyped together. Sorry for kicking everyone out beforehand...
ま、みんなでちょっと盛り上がりたいです
Well, I really want everyone to get hyped with me!
この曲で、えー、次の、あ、この衣装で、え、次の曲、行っちゃうぞ！
With this song, and, uh, in this outfit, let's dive right into the next song!
触れ合えば don't be afraid
When we touch, don't be afraid.
楽しい 嬉しい 共有し (前進)
Share the fun and joy (Forward!)
触れ合えば yes, we are friends
When we touch, yes, we are friends.
浮き立つウキウキのステップで 跳ねるリズムカルに let's go
With an upbeat, lively step, let's bounce rhythmically, let's go!
どこへだって運んであげる
I'll carry you anywhere you want.
さながら夢の詰まったオモチャ箱 組み立ててからのお楽しみ
Like a toy box filled with dreams, the real fun starts after assembly!
hi
どこでだって遊んであげる
I'll play with you anywhere you go.
ラッパのゾウさんにギターのクマと dj tigerも従えて
With an elephant on the trumpet, a bear on guitar, and DJ Tiger in tow!
その土地土地で make your ドキドキ day
In every single town, make your thrilling day!
つまりあちこちで 余興のカチコミで
Meaning everywhere you look, filled with side-show chatter.
君の街へと大行進 お騒がせしております アイムソーリー
A grand parade marching through your streets, making quite a fuss—sorry not sorry!
キラリぴかぴかの電飾にかげた 魔法に目を奪われる you & you
Draped in sparkling, twinkling lights, you and you are mesmerized by the magic!
もう注目の的
Now we're the center of attention,
みんなが噂してる (i know)
Everyone's whispering about it (I know).
朝から晩までハイテンション 千客万来の大盛況
High energy from morning till night, a massive turnout of visitors!
お待たせ 次は君の番
Thanks for waiting, next up is your turn!
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる (get you)
Shifting interests of yours, we'll make them stay right here forever (Get you!)
ma-ma-ma-ma-ma, marvelous
次の町へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで
To the next town, come take my hand and let's go, hey, come along!
まさにフェスティバル 仲良しこよし 高揚し 振り切れちゃう興奮のメーター
Truly a festival, getting along swimmingly, high spirits pushing excitement off the charts!
掌握テクニカル 求められてるの理解してるが故のプレイヤー
Sleight-of-hand technique, playing the part while fully understanding what is desired.
はいこちらどうぞ 含みある声で誘えば現れる本性
Step right in please, inviting you with a sweet voice reveals our true nature.
失くしてあげる情緒不安定にマイナスな感情 取り除くエモーション
Wiping away your emotional instability and negative feelings, removing the emotion!
なんだか寂しそう ねぇ何が足りない? (ない?)
Feeling a bit lonely? Hey, what's missing? (What?)
閉園の時間になっても帰りたがらない (ない)
Even when closing time arrives, you don't want to go home. (No!)
オーキードーキー 差し伸べる手に感じる温もりが何よりものアンサー
Okey-dokey, the warmth felt in the outstretched hand is the best answer of all.
ようこそ今日から君もうちの一員だね
Welcome, starting today you're one of us too!
はいそれでは repeat after me
Alright then, repeat after me!
弄じられても repeat after me
Even if you're toyed with, repeat after me!
祭の後 毎度お馴染み
After the festival, as always, familiar rumors.
誰かが噂してる (i know)
Someone is whispering (I know).
「町から人がいなくなってる、奴等が何やら企んでる。」
"People are vanishing from town, the scoundrels must be plotting something."
はてさて 次は誰の番
Well now, whose turn is next?
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる (get you)
Shifting interests of yours, we'll make them stay right here forever (Get you!)
ma-ma-ma-ma-ma, marvelous
次の町へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで
To the next town, come take my hand and let's go, hey, come along!
いくつもの街を巡り巡って
Wandering through countless towns,
浮かない顔の君にあげる good day
Bringing a good day to you with that gloomy face!
空飛ぶ車 ネオンきらめく七色ローラーコースター
Flying carriages, neon-glowing seven-color rollercoasters!
ラブリー観覧車 光るキャンディーに 誰も彼もノックアウト
Lovely Ferris wheels, glowing candy—everyone gets knocked out!
この歌声が聞こえてきたのなら
If this song happens to reach your ears,
君の町の番
It's your town's turn!
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる (get you)
Shifting interests of yours, we'll make them stay right here forever (Get you!)
ma-ma-ma-ma-ma, marvelous
次の町へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで
To the next town, come take my hand and let's go, hey, come along!
welcome to the funfair, さぁ皆一緒に come & join us
Welcome to the funfair, come and join us!
はあ、ということで、ファンフェアでした！
Phew, and with that, that was "Funfair"!
どうでした？めちゃくちゃアップテンポで楽しいラップソングになっている曲です。
How was it? It's a super upbeat, fun rap song.
えー、みんな、楽しんでいただけましたか？
Did everyone enjoy it?
え、そしてですね、今回はですね、フロートっていう乗り物まで用意してもらいました！ありがとうございます！
And also, this time we even had a float prepared for us! Thank you so much!
すごいよね、これ。
Isn't that amazing?
今回はね、ちょっとパレードしてみたいなと思ったんでね、ご用意させていただきました。ありがとうございます！みんなもありがとー！
This time I really wanted to do a parade, so we got it prepared. Thank you! Thank you all too!
さて、そろそろ、え、恒例の告知タイムへ
Now then, it's almost time for our usual announcement segment!
行きましょうか。あ、でもね、まだ、
Let's get started. Ah, but you know,
あの、終わらないので、ちょっとまあ、あの、終わる、ほんとに最後まで見てってほしいんですけど、
it's not over yet, so I want you to watch right to the very end.
え、今年の告知はですね、二つあります。
Um, this year's announcements are... two things.
あ、これだと4か。二つあります。
Ah, wait, that's four. Two things!
では、え、まず一つ目は、こちら、今年も出します！不知火フレア生誕祭グッズ2025！
Now, first of all, is this one! Releasing this year as well! Shiranui Flare's Birthday Goods 2025!
はい、気になる内容、みんなで一緒に見ていきましょう！
Yes, let's check out the details together everyone!
一つ目は、こちら！アクリルジオラマスタンド！
The first one is this! Acrylic diorama stand!
さきやひろ先生に描いていただきました！かわいいでしょ！
Drawn by Sakiya Hiro-sensei! Isn't it cute?!
この衣装もですね、え、さきやひろ先生にデザインしていただきました！本当にありがとうございます！
This outfit was also designed by Sakiya Hiro-sensei! Thank you so much!
かわいい！今回ね、衣装に合わせて神秘的な感じに仕上げていただきました！ありがとうございます！
So cute! And it's finished in a mystical style to match the outfit! Thank you!
え、続いて、え、二つ目は、こちら！ランダムラバーストラップ！
Uh, next, um, the second one is this! Random rubber strap!
ま4周年にもね、出させていただいたんですけど、ま今回はですね、違うパターンのラバーストラップです。
We released some for the 4th anniversary too, but this time it's a different pattern of rubber straps.
なんか、ん？なんか見たことない衣装とかもちょっとあるけど、まあ、いっか、ま一旦ね、ま一旦、いいや。
Like, hm? There are some outfits I haven't seen before too, but oh well, let's leave it at that!
えー、まあ、今回もね、いろんな衣装出てますので、ぜひぜひ、よろしくお願いしますっていうことで、
Um, various outfits are out this time too, so please check them out!
イラストはですね、4周年記念グッズと同じく、え、いつもお世話になっておりますすずみあうは先生です！いつも可愛いイラストありがとうございます！
The illustration is by Suzumi Auha-sensei, who always takes care of us! Thank you always for the cute illustrations!
え、次は、こちら！ルミナスパーカー！
Uh, next is this! Luminous Parka!
今回の新賞を表現したパーカーなんですけど、名前とかついてる方がなんか言いやすいかなとかって思ったので、ルミナス衣装と、まあ名づけております。
It's a parka expressing the new song, but having a name attached makes it easier to refer to, so I've named it the Luminous outfit.
男女ともに買いやすいデザインにしてもらえましたので、ぜひぜひ皆さん、おとこ…男の子女の子関係なく、可愛くかっこよく着てもらえたら嬉しいです！
It's designed to be easily wearable for both men and women, so I'd be super happy if everyone could wear it!
サイズも大きいので重ね着もしやすいです！ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
The sizes are large so it's easy to layer too. Please definitely check it out!
次は、こちら！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー ルミナス衣装ver.！うぇーい、かわいいね！
Next is this! Plush keychain Luminous outfit ver.! Yay, so cute!
とに引き続きぬいぐるみキーホルダーが出ます！今回は新衣装のルミナス衣装バージョンです！
Following last year, a plush keychain is coming out, this time in the new Luminous outfit version!
リボンあしらったこの衣装、残りの白いバージョンのほうですね、こちらが出ますので、
This outfit with ribbons, the remaining white version, will be released,
ぜひぜひバッグとか、旅行とかね、どこにでも連れてって一緒にフレアとお写真撮ってくれると嬉しいです！おうちに飾ってくれても嬉しいよ！
so please take it with you on trips and take pictures with Flare! Displaying it at home is also great!
フルセット購入の特典は、こちら！
The full set purchase bonus is this!
数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製サインに加えて直筆メッセージが入ります！
The limited quantity version includes a foil-stamped duplicate signature plus a handwritten message!
通常バージョンにもですね、箔押し複製サインと箔押し複製メッセージが入りますので、直筆が欲しい方は、先着順となってしまうんですけど、早めに数量限定版をご購入ください！
The regular version also includes a foil-stamped signature and message, so if you want the handwritten one, please purchase early!
買えなかったよ、数量限定買えなかったよって方も、ちょっと長めのメッセージを、複製のほうは書かせていただきます。なので、数量買えなくても、ぜひ悲しまないで買ってくれると嬉しいです！
Even if you can't get the limited quantity, I'll write a longer message for the duplicate version, so please don't be sad and buy it!
さらにですね、フルセット特典として、昨年の9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
Furthermore, as a full set bonus, a card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game released since last September will be included!
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルカードショップで購入された方のみ対象となります！
The cards are only for those who purchased from the Hololive Production Official Card Shop!
特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるキーカードを、推しホロメンカードです！
The card included as a bonus is a key card that lets you showcase your oshi, an oshi holomem card!
カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページにてご確認ください！
Please check the homepage for details on the card and how to play!
カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご容赦ください！
Please note that the cards are in Japanese only!
お知らせ二つ目は、こちら！どどん！
The second announcement is this! Ta-da!
新曲が…新曲が出ます！タイトルは「薄明光線」です！堀江晶太さんに作っていただきました！
A new song is coming out! The title is "Hakumei Kousen"! Produced by Shouta Horie-san!
さっきのラバーストラップで見たことない衣装があったなみたいな感じだと思ったんですけど、実はこのMVの中でなんと着ている衣装となります！
I thought it was like an outfit I hadn't seen before on the rubber strap, but it's actually the outfit worn in this MV!
このあと配信終了後にMVが公開されます！
The MV will be released right after this stream ends!
各種音楽サイトでは24時からリリースとなっておりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
It will be released starting at midnight on various music sites, so please look forward to it!
さて、次がラストの曲になりますが、薄明光線、どんな曲か、公開前に聴きたいな、歌いたいな！
Now, the next will be the last song, but "Hakumei Kousen," what kind of song is it? I wanted to listen to it before release!
どうしようかな、歌っちゃおうかな、歌おうかな、どうしようか、いいよ！ということで、今回「薄明光線」公開前に歌っちゃおうかなと思います！
What should I do, should I sing it, okay! With that, I think I'll sing a bit of "Hakumei Kousen" before its release!
改めてまして、今日は来てくれてありがとうございました！それでは、ラスト
Once again, thank you for coming today! Well then...
の、締めくくる、えー曲聞いてください。
Please listen to the final, um, song.
白明光線
Luminescent Ray
オレンジの坂道を上りゆけば
Climbing up the orange slope,
懐かしい誰かがそこで待ってる
someone nostalgic is waiting there.
「また、気のせいか」とおどけながら
Jokingly saying, "Just my imagination again?"
影をすり抜ける
I slip right through the shadows.
これはいつからだっけ まるで夢を見ているようで
How long has it been? It feels just like a dream.
誰かに触れることもなくなって
Having lost the ability to touch anyone,
思い出せない名前 だけど大切な
a name I can't remember, yet such
思い出
precious memories.
わたしは誰に逢いたいのだろう
Who is it that I want to meet?
誰をなくして泣いているのだろう
Who did I lose that I'm crying for?
知らないメロディを口ずさむ
Humming a melody I don't know,
いつか此処で笑ってたあなたと
with you, who was smiling here once...
いじらしい天使が残したのは
What the endearing angel left behind
一度だけ世界と結び合うリボン
was a ribbon binding us to the world just once.
姿かたちの向こう側へ 祈りは込めるもの
Beyond our physical forms, prayers are held within.
伝えたいことがあった
There was something I wanted to tell you,
だけど
but
いつもうまく言えなかった
I could never say it right.
声をなくしてやっと叫ぶ
Losing my voice, I finally scream—
なんて情けない亡霊だろう
what a pathetic ghost I am.
ずっと愛している
I've always loved you.
届くことのない歌と あなたが携えた花を
With a song that won't reach you and the flowers you carried,
たった一度だけ結び合おう
let's bind ourselves together just this once.
思い出せなくなって あなたに逢いに行く
Even if I forget, I'll go to meet you.
光が進む 顔は見えない
Light moves forward, though I can't see your face.
それでも何故かあなたと分かる
Yet for some reason, I know it's you.
知らないメロディを口ずさむ
Humming a melody I don't know,
あなたに教わったんだ
you taught it to me.
わたしは誰 誰でもいいよ
Who am I? Anyone is fine.
あなたの傍で泣けるのならば
As long as I can cry by your side.
知らない色をした空が来る
A sky of unknown colors arrives.
いつか此処で笑ってたあなたと
With you, who was smiling here once...
あなたと
...with you...